Guide to the Albert Galloway Keller Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1898-(1900-1956)-1971; Series I; 6.0 linear feet (15 boxes)
  - Lawrence, William Ewart, 1930, 1937, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 322)
  - Lawrence, William Ewart (*), 1941-1945 (Box 9, Folder 323)
  - Leach, G. Sidney, 1913, 1942-1943, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 324-325)
  - Leavens, Dickson H. -- Ledyard, Henry Scott Leavitt, 1911, undated, 1914, 1932, 1930, 1936, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 326)
    See also: box 13, folder 489
  - Lee, Alfred McClung, 1937, 1939, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 327)
  - Lee, Mrs. Alfred McClung (Elizabeth Briant), 1935, 1946, 1948, undated (Box 9, Folder 328)
  - Lee, Burton J., Jr. -- Leistner, Karl, 1913, 1921, 1926, 1942-1949 (Box 9, Folder 329)
  - Lerner, Max, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 330)
  - Lewis, Arthur F., 1942 (Box 9, Folder 331)
  - Lewis, Sinclair, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 332)
  - Lewiston Daily Sun, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 333)
  - Leyburn, James G., 1933, 1937, 1942, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 334)
  - Library of Congress -- Life, 1915, 1944, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 335)
  - Lindenberg, Ottilia, 1931-1933 (Box 9, Folder 336)
    See also: box 6, folder 207-208 See also: box 6, folder 209-217 See also: box 10, folder 382-388
  - Lindsay, Samuel M., 1901 (Box 9, Folder 337)
  - Lippert, Julius, 1902 (Box 9, Folder 338)
  - Little, Brown & Company -- Loeb, Edwin M., 1922, 1930, 1937-1938, 1941-1947, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 339)
  - Loetscher, Eugene A. -- Lohmann, Carl A., 1931-1932, 1942, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 340)
  - Longmans, Green & Co. (*), 1901-1905, 1907, 1909, 1916, 1926, 1938, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 341)
    See also: box 16, folder 605-606 See also: box 16, folder 607 See also: box 53, folder 1431-1433
  - Loomis, Edward N. -- Luce, Clare Booth, 1915-1916, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 342)
  - Luce, Henry (*), 1940-1944, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 343)
  - Luce, J. W. -- Lumley, Frederick E., 1913, 1915, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 344)
  - Luquens, Frederick B., 1916, 1918, undated (Box 9, Folder 345)
  - Luquiens, Huc-Mazelet -- Lynch, Roger S., 1941-1943, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 346)
  - McAfee, C. B. -- McDaniels, W., 1913-1918, 1937, 1942, 1943, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 347)
  - McGraw, Arthur B. (*), 1932, 1939, 1940, 1942-1944, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 348)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company -- McMichael, Harrison, 1910, 1942-1947, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 349)
  - Macmillan Co. (*), 1913-1915, 1918, 1921, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 350-352)
  - Macmillan Co., 1930-1931 August (Box 9, Folder 353)
  - Macmillan Co. (*), 1931 September (Box 9, Folder 354)
  - Macmillan Co. (*), 1931, 1935, 1938, 1940-1943, 1947, undated (Box 9, Folder 355)
    See also: box 16, folder 614-618 See also: box 17, folder 619-621 See also: box 53, folder 1428
  - Maddox, John Lee (*), 1914-1917 (Box 10, Folder 356)
  - Maguire, Walter N. -- Mason, O., 1904, 1932, 1936, 1942, 1947-1948, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 357)
  - Mateja, Edwin C. -- Mayer, William R., 1912, 1915-1919, undated, 1932, 1941-1943 (Box 10, Folder 358)
  - Mead, Penfield -- Meeks, Everett V., 1933, 1938, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 359)
  - Melhorn, Elsa Keller (Mrs. Nathan R.), 1916, 1943, 1948-1949 (Box 10, Folder 360)
  - Melhorn, Nathan R., 1942, 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 361)
  - Mellon, Paul, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 361a)
  - Melvin, Ann Delia, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 362)
  - Mencken, H. L. (*), 1932-1933, 1942-1943, 1947, undated (Box 10, Folder 363)
    See also, box 1, folder 3 See also: box 37, folder 958
  - Mendell, Clarence W., 1927, 1931, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 364)
  - Mendell, Clarence W., 1935-1936, 1942, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 365)
    See also: box 7, folder 229
  - Merritt, Alfred K. -- Middletown Citizens' Committee, 1911, 1925, 1944, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 366)
  - Miller, Lillian K. -- Millis, Walter, 1930, 1935, 1937, 1946, 1944-1945, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 367)
  - Mims, S. L. -- Moore, Arthur, Jr., 1913, 1915, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 368)
  - Moore, Barrington, Jr., 1942-1943, 1945, 1947, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 369)
  - Moore, Jared S. -- Moore, William C., 1916, 1933, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 370)
  - Morris, E. P., 1932, 1934, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 371)
  - Morrison, A. W. -- Munroe, Vernon, 1915, 1920, 1932-1935, 1942, 1944, 1946, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 372)
  - Munson, Edward L., 1918-1919, 1941, 1944, undated (Box 10, Folder 373)
    See also: box 15, folder 598
  - Munson, Marta J. -- Myers, Walter, 1903, 1911, 1917, 1924, 1928, 1942, 1946, undated (Box 10, Folder 374)
  - Nahum, Louis H. -- Naman, Wilfred W., 1938-1939, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 375)
  - The Nation (*), 1906, 1909, 1913, 1915-1916 (Box 10, Folder 376)
    See also; box 5, folder 143
  - National Economic Council -- Neergard, Paul J., 1907, 1916-1917, 1923, 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 377)
  - New England Mutual Life Insurance Co., 1936-1938, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 378)
  - The New Republic, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 379)
  - New York Times -- Northrop, FilmerS. C., 1938, 1942, 1944, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 380)
  - Nordland, Tante, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 381)
  - Nordland, Vater, 1931-1933 (Box 10, Folder 382-385)
  - Nordland, Vater (*), 1934 (Box 10, Folder 386)
  - Nordland, Vater, 1935-1936 (Box 10, Folder 387)
  - Nordland, Vater, 1937, undated (Box 10, Folder 388)
    See also: box 6, folder 207-208 See also: box 6, folder 209-217 See also: box 9, folder 336
  - Notestein, Wallace, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 389)
  - Oertel, Hans -- Oler, Weslen M., 1912, 1932, 1937, 1940, 1943-1947, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 390)
  - O'Neill, Emmet -- Osgood, Cornelius, 1916-1917, 1933, 1942, 1946, 1948-1949, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 391)
  - Ostrander, Harry -- Oxford University Press, 1913-1914, 1924-1925, 1931, 1939, 1942, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 392)
  - Paavola, Edwin K. (*), 1942-1946 (Box 10, Folder 393)
  - Page, Alex R. -- Parkins, Henry A., 1914, 1916, 1932-1934, 1944, 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 394)
  - Parnall, Christopher -- Parnall, Emma, 1942-1945 (Box 10, Folder 395)
  - Parsons, Edward S., 1911-1912 (Box 10, Folder 396)
  - Patrick, Hugh T. -- Paxton, Thomas B., 1929, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 397)
  - Peck, George, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 398)
  - Peck, Martin -- Persoff, Albert M., 1915, 1942-1945 (Box 10, Folder 399)
  - Peter, Julius C., 1911, 1912, 1914 September (Box 10, Folder 400)
  - Peter, J. C. (*), 1914 October-1914 December (Box 10, Folder 401)
  - Peter, J. C., 1915 January (Box 10, Folder 402)
  - Peter, J. C. (*), 1915 February-1918 (Box 10, Folder 403-407)
  - Peter, J. C. (*), 1919-1924 (Box 11, Folder 408-414)
  - Peter, J. C., 1925 (Box 11, Folder 415-416)
  - Peter, J. C. (*), 1926-1929 February-November (Box 11, Folder 417-423)
  - Peter, J. C., 1929 December (Box 11, Folder 424)
  - Peter, J. C. (*), 1930 January-September (Box 11, Folder 425-427)
  - Peter, J. C., 1930 November-1931 May (Box 11, Folder 428-429)
  - Peter, J. C. (*), 1931 July-1932 August (Box 11, Folder 430-431)
  - Peter, J. C., 1932 September-December (Box 11, Folder 432)
  - Peter, J. C. (*), 1933-1937 (Box 11, Folder 433-434)
  - Peter, J. C., 1938-1940 March (Box 11, Folder 435)
  - Peter, J. C. (*), 1940 May-1942 (Box 11, Folder 436-437)
  - Peter, J. C., 1943 February-March (Box 11, Folder 438)
  - Peter, J. C. (*), 1943 April-November (Box 11, Folder 439)
  - Peter, J. C., 1944-1946 January-May (Box 11, Folder 440-441)
  - Peter, J. C. (*), 1946 June-1954, undated (Box 11, Folder 442-446)
  - Peter, J. C., 1955-1956 (Box 11, Folder 447)
  - Peter, J. C., undated (Box 11, Folder 448)
    See also: box 12, folder 450-471 See also: box 50, folder 1317-1395 See also: box 15, folder 599-600
  - Peter, Marie, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 449)
  - Peter, William F. (*), 1916, 1932, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 450)
  - Peter, W. F. (*), 1944 January-1948 August (Box 12, Folder 451-463)
  - Peter, W. F., 1948 September-December (Box 12, Folder 464)
  - Peter, W. F. (*), 1949 January-Jun, 1950-1955 (Box 12, Folder 465-470)
  - Peter, William F., undated (Box 12, Folder 471)
    See also: box 10, folder 400-448 See also: box 15, folder 601 See also: box 51, folder 1379-1395
  - Peterson, Samuel, 1903 (Box 12, Folder 472)
  - Phelps, William Lyon (*), 1911-1914, 1928-1937, 1940-1942 (Box 12, Folder 473)
  - Phillips, Andrew W. -- Purcell, Edward, 1911, 1915-1918, 1921, 1924, 1942-1945, undated (Box 12, Folder 474)
  - Pratt, Ann S. (Box 12, Folder 474)
    See: box 14, folder 560
  - Ragatz, Lowell Joseph -- Ray, Frank, 1913, 1934, 1942, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 475)
  - Read, Leonard E. (*), 1944, 1946-1949, 1954, undated (Box 12, Folder 476)
  - Reed, Stephen W. -- Reilly, James A., 1937, 1943, 1950, undated (Box 12, Folder 477)
  - Resor, Stanley (*), 1944, 1948-1949 (Box 12, Folder 478)
  - Rieder, Florence -- Robb, Roger, 1903, 1915, 1933-1934, 1942, 1945, undated (Box 12, Folder 479)
  - Robbins, R.W. -- Root, R.T., 1913, 1917, 1942, 1944-1945, 1946, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 480)
  - Rosenthal, Charles, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 481)
  - Rosenthal, Charles (*), 1944-1945 (Box 12, Folder 482)
  - Royce, Alexander B., 1915 (Box 12, Folder 483)
  - Russell, Fletcher A. (*), 1948 (Box 12, Folder 484)
  - Rossi -- Rowe, H. Gordon, 1933, 1935, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 485)
  - Sachs, Louis -- Sargent, Porter, 1912, 1916, 1922, 1935, 1942, 1946-1948 (Box 12, Folder 486)
  - Saturday Evening Post (*), 1942-1945, undated (Box 13, Folder 487)
  - Saturday Review of Books (*), 1927-1929, 1942, 1944-1945, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 488)
  - Saunders, Antoine B. -- Scott, Hugh L., 1911, 1923, 1930, 1934 1937, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 489)
  - Scott, Hugh L. (Box 13, Folder 489)
    See also: box 9, folder 326
  - Schatz, Albert -- Schevill, Rudolph, 1913-1914, 1943, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 490)
  - Scientific Monthly -- Serrat, W.D., 1913-1914, 1916, 1926, 1942, 1945-1946 (Box 13, Folder 491)
  - Seymour, Charles (*), 1932-1933, 1938-1940, 1942, 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 492)
  - Seymour, D. L., 1902, 1918, undated (Box 13, Folder 493)
  - Shaw, Ralph M., 1933-1934 (Box 13, Folder 494-495)
  - Shaw, Ralph M., 1936 (Box 13, Folder 496)
    See also: box 25, folder 743-754
  - Shaw, Ralph M., 1937-1938, 1942-1946, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 497-501)
  - Sheldon, Charles, 1904, 1905, 1913-1914 (Box 13, Folder 502)
  - Shepard, Brooks, 1913, 1941, 1943, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 503)
  - Shepard, Walter B. -- Simley, Ralph, 1924, 1930, 1932-1934, 1936, 1942-1943, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 504)
  - Shouse, Jouett (Box 13, Folder 504)
    See also: box 13, folder 496
  - Simmons, Leo W., 1942-1943 (Box 13, Folder 505)
  - Simon, Barbara, 1932-1935 (Box 13, Folder 506)
  - Sinn, Ephraim E. -- Small, Albion Woodbury, 1913-1915, 1945-1946 (Box 13, Folder 507)
  - Smith, Dorland (*), 1918, 1923, 1926, 1928, 1933, 1939, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 508)
  - Smith, Elliot Dunlap, 1920, 1931, 1937, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 509)
  - Smith, George Arthur -- Smith, Vernon A., 1912, 1915, 1918, 1921, 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 510)
  - Smithley, Robert L. (*), 1942-1944, 1946-1948, 1951, undated (Box 13, Folder 511)
  - Society for the Advancement of Education -- Sperry, Frederick N., 1912, 1927, 1936, 1943, 1945, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 512)
  - Southworth, E. F. (Box 13, Folder 512)
    See also: box 5, folder 150-152
  - Starr, Harris E., 1932-1933, 1939, 1943, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 513)
  - Steeble, Frederick A. -- Steele, Thomas A., 1916, 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 514)
  - Stephens, Howard, Jr. -- Stevenson, R. I., 1938, 1942, 1945, undated (Box 13, Folder 515)
  - Stewart, George -- Steyne, Alan, 1910, 1918, 1933, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 516)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps, Jr. (*), 1901-1902, 1905, 1907-1909, 1911-1914, 1918-1919, 1922, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 517)
  - Stokes Co., Frederick A. (*), 1932-1933 (Box 13, Folder 518-519)
  - Stone, Stanley -- Sullivan, Russell, 1917, 1942, 1945, 1947, 1951, undated (Box 13, Folder 520)
  - Sumner, Alfred R. -- Sumner, Elliot, 1910, 1915, 1921, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 521)
  - Sumner, George S., 1916 (Box 13, Folder 522)
  - Sumner, Graham, 1910-1911, 1917, 1921, 1933, undated (Box 13, Folder 523)
  - Sumner, Stanley J., 1942 (Box 13, Folder 524)
  - Sumner, Mrs. William Graham, (Jeannie) (*), 1908-1910, 1912-1916, undated (Box 13, Folder 525)
  - Sumner Club, William Graham, 1909, 1918, 1920-1924, 1939, 1943, undated (Box 13, Folder 526-527)
  - Svirsky, Leon -- Syngamuki, John, 1920-1921, 1942-1943, 1946, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 528)
  - Taft, Horace D. (*), 1916, 1933, 1940, 1942, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 529)
  - Taft, Robert A., 1941, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 530)
  - Tagu, Tirouis -- Thorne, D. R., 1907, 1933-1934, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 531)
  - Thurber, C. H. (*), 1910, 1912-1913, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 532)
  - Thurber, C. H., 1916 (Box 13, Folder 533)
  - Thurber, C. H. (*), 1917-1919, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 534)
  - Thurber, C. H. (*), 1923-1926, 1930, 1932-1934, undated (Box 13, Folder 535)
  - Tilney, Frederick A., Dr., 1934 (Box 14, Folder 536)
  - Time, 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 537)
  - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1933, 1935-1938, 1941-1942 (Box 14, Folder 538-539)
  - Todd, A. J. (*), 1911-1917, 1933, 1942-1943 (Box 14, Folder 540)
  - Troxell, Janet Camp -- Tyson, Floyd T., 1925, 1943, undated (Box 14, Folder 541)
  - Tompkins, B. A. -- Troughton, W., 1946-1947, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 542)
  - United States, War Department, 1918 (Box 14, Folder 543)
  - University of Chicago -- Usher, Neville T., 1925, 1933, 1949, undated (Box 14, Folder 544)
  - Utley, Frederick B., 1943 April-August (Box 14, Folder 545)
  - Utley, Frederick B. (*), 1943 September-1944 (Box 14, Folder 546)
    See also: box 4, folder 112-115 See also: box 4, folder 137 See also: box 5, folder 157-161 See also: box 14, folder 578
  - Vaill, Dudley L., 1931-1932, 1936, 1938, 1941-1945, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 547-549)
  - Vaill, Dudley L. (*), 1949 (Box 14, Folder 550)
  - Valentine, Alan -- Viehmann, H., Jr., 1914-1915, 1932, 1935-1936, 1944, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 551)
  - Viking Press -- Von Mohrenschildt, D. S., 1914-1915, 1925, 1942-1944 (Box 14, Folder 552)
  - Wadsworth, J. J. -- Wall Street Journal, 1905, 1915, 1925, 1935, 1943-1944 (Box 14, Folder 553)
  - Walker, Amasa (Box 14, Folder 553)
    See also: box 16, folder 605-606
  - Walworth, Arthur C., Jr. (*), 1931-1935, 1944, 1948, 1955, undated (Box 14, Folder 554)
  - Wang, Chengting T. (*), 1911-1912, 1916, 1941, undated (Box 14, Folder 555)
  - Wang, K. S., 1944 (Box 14, Folder 556)
  - Ward, Artemus (*), 1910, 1912, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 557)
    See also: box 16, folder 614-618
  - Ward, Artemus, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 558)
  - Ward, David -- Washburn (E.L.) Co., Inc., 1935, 1942-1945 (Box 14, Folder 559)
    See also: box 1, folder 18
  - Watstein, Harry -- Webster, Frederic D., 1934, 1942-1944, 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 560)
  - Webster, Hutton, 1916-1918, 1942-1944 (Box 14, Folder 561)
  - Webster, William E. -- Weyer, Ed, 1914-1916, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 562)
  - Whalen, Robert E. -- White, Edward, 1916, 1928, 1942-1943, 1946, 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 563)
  - White, Francis, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 564)
  - White, Henry C., 1933 (Box 14, Folder 565)
  - Whitney, H. Leroy -- Wight, Eliot L., 1935, 1941-1942, 1945, 1946, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 566)
  - Williams, A. Shaller -- Williams, J. M., 1913, 1915, 1941, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 567)
  - Wilson, Edwin B., 1946 (Box 14, Folder 568)
  - Wilson, Lucy James, 1913-1914 (Box 14, Folder 569)
  - Wilson, Thomas J. -- Wyant, G. E., 1900, 1904, 1909, 1916, 1918, 1932, 1942-1943, 1951 (Box 14, Folder 570)
  - Yale University, Associates in the Science of Society. Dean's Office, 1914, 1916-1917, 1925, 1932, 1938, 1940, 1945, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 571)
  - Yale University, Department of Sociology. Personnel Director, 1921, 1924, 1926, 1928-1930, 1945, undated (Box 14, Folder 572)
  - Yale University Press, 1913-1914, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 573)
  - Yale University Press (*), 1917-1918 (Box 14, Folder 574-575)
  - Yale University Press (*), 1924, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 576)
    See also: box 37, folder 914-915 See also: box 17, folder 621-722
  - Yale University Press (*), 1927, 1931-1933, 1942-1947, undated (Box 14, Folder 577-578)
  - Yale University, Secretary's Office (*), 1905-1906, 1923, 1929-1932, 1938, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 579)
  - Yale University, Treasurer's Office (*), 1920-1930, 1938, 1940, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 580)
    See also: box 50, folder 1329-1353
  - Yale University, Yale Review (*), 1915, 1926, 1937, 1942, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 581)
  - Unidentified correspondence, 1912-1916, 1924-1925, 1931-1934, 1937-1939, 1942-1949, 1952, 1955, undated (Box 15, Folder 582-585)
  - Correspondence not to Keller
    - American Association of University Professors -- Brady, Tom P., 1907, 1916, 1956-1957, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 586)
    - California State Library -- Daume, Selden B., 1929, 1931, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 587)
    - Day, Clarence, Jr., 1907, 1912, 1919, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 587a)
      See also: box 2, folder 59-97
    - Day, Clive -- Goodenough, Edwin R., 1912, 1916, 1941, 1944, 1957, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 587b)
    - Granite, Mark, 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 588)
    - Gould, Charles W. -- Harvard University Press, 1928, 1950-1951, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 589)
    - Hastings, Hudson B. -- Keeler, Floyd M., 1916, 1921, 1935, 1945, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 590)
    - Keller, Carl T. (*), 1913, 1915, 1931-1933, 1935-1939, 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 591-592)
    - Keller, Carl T., 1944-1945, 1948-1953 (Box 15, Folder 593)
      See also: box 7, folder 222-297
    - Keller, Caroline, 1948, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 594)
    - Keller, Deane, 1923, 1932-1933, 1935, 1937-1938, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 595)
    - Keller, K.T. -- Keller, Ralph H., 1944, undated (Box 15, Folder 596)
    - Lee, Alfred McClung -- Oxford University Press, 1928, 1931, 1933, 1935, 1937, 1944, 1949, 1951, 1956-1957 (Box 15, Folder 597)
    - Munson, Edward L., 1918 (Box 15, Folder 598)
      See also: box 10, folder 373
    - Peter, Julius C., 1933, 1956-1957 June (Box 15, Folder 599)
    - Peter, Julius C., 1957 Jul, 1965, 1968, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 600)
      See also: box 10, folder 400-448
    - Peter, William F. (*), 1950-1953, 1955-1957 (Box 15, Folder 601)
      See also: box 12, folder 450-457
    - Phillips, Andrew W. -- Stokes, A. P., 1900, 1925, 1931, 1933, 1943, 1949, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 602)
    - Sumner, Eliot -- Sumner, William Graham, 1898, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 603)
    - United Parents Association of New York City, Inc. -- Yale University Psychology, 1910, 1926, 1928, 1932, 1946, 1960-1961, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 604)
- Writings, 1894-1952; Series II; 9.25 linear feet (26 boxes)
  Published Books is arranged chronologically.
  Unpublished Books is arranged chronologically.
  Fiction is arranged by form: poetry, drama, novels.
  Lectures, Essays and Notebooks is arranged chronologically.
  Miscellaneous Writings is arranged chronologically.
  - Published Books
    - Homeric Society
      - Proofsheets, 1901 (Box 16, Folder 605)
      - Book reviews, 1902 (Box 16, Folder 606)
      - Introductory note to reprint, 1906 September 1 (Box 16, Folder 606a)
        See also: box 9, folder 341 See also: box 14, folder 553 See also: box 53, folder 1431-1432
    - Queries in Ethnography: book reviews, 1903 (Box 16, Folder 607)
      See also: box 9, folder 341 See also: box 53, folder 1430-1432
    - Keller's introduction to William Graham Sumner's Essays
      - Proofsheets, 1911 (Box 16, Folder 608-609)
    - War and Other Essays, edited by A. G. Keller: book review, 1912 (Box 16, Folder 610)
      See also: box 53, folder 1430
    - Commercial and Industrial Geography: book reviews, 1912 (Box 16, Folder 611)
    - Earth Hunger and Other Essays, edited by A. G. Keller: book reviews, 1914 (Box 16, Folder 612)
    - The Challenge of Facts and Other Essays, edited by A. G. Keller: book reviews, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 613)
    - Societal Evolution
      - TMs and proofsheets, pp. 1-95, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 614)
      - TMs and proofsheets, pp. 102-200, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 615)
      - Proofsheets, pp. 201-301, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 616)
      - TMs and proofsheets, pp. 302-425, Index, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 617)
      - Book reviews, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 618)
        See also: box 2, folder 47 See also: box 9, folders 350-355 See also: box 14, folder 557 See also: box 53, folder 1428
    - Through War to Peace
      - TMs, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 619-620)
      - Book reviews, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 621)
        See also: box 9, folder 350-355 See also: box 53, folder 1428
    - Science of Society
      - First draft of Part I, AMs, Circa 1911-1927
        - pp. 1-100 (Box 17, Folder 622)
        - pp. 101-200 (Box 17, Folder 623)
        - pp. 201-277 (Box 17, Folder 624)
      - Draft of Part I, Chapters I-IV, AMs (Box 17, Folder 625)
      - Part I, Chapter II, AMs (Box 17, Folder 626)
      - Part I, Chapter III, Sections 45-48, AMs (Box 17, Folder 627)
      - Early draft of a portion of Part II, Chapter VII, AMs (Box 17, Folder 628)
      - Early draft of Part II, AMs
        - Chapter VIII (Box 17, Folder 629)
        - Chapter IX (Box 17, Folder 630)
        - Chapter X (Box 18, Folder 631)
        - Chapter XI (Box 18, Folder 632)
        - Chapter XII (Box 18, Folder 633)
        - Chapter XIII (Box 18, Folder 634)
      - Draft of Part II, AMs
        - Chapter IV (Box 18, Folder 635)
        - Chapter V (Box 18, Folder 636)
        - Chapter VI (Box 18, Folder 637)
        - Chapter VII (Box 18, Folder 638)
        - Chapter VIII (Box 18, Folder 639)
        - Chapter IX (Box 18, Folder 640)
        - Chapter X (Box 18, Folder 641)
        - Chapter XI (Box 18, Folder 642)
        - Chapter XII (Box 18, Folder 643)
        - Chapter XIII (Box 18, Folder 644)
      - Draft of Part III, AMs
        - Chapter XIV (Box 18, Folder 645)
        - Chapter XV (Box 18, Folder 646)
        - Chapter XVI (Box 18, Folder 647)
        - Chapter XVII (Box 19, Folder 648)
        - Chapter XVIII (Box 19, Folder 649)
        - Chapter XIX (Box 19, Folder 650)
        - Chapter XX (Box 19, Folder 651)
      - Draft of Part IV, AMs
        - Chapter XXI (Box 19, Folder 652)
        - Chapter XXI, AMs and TMs (Box 19, Folder 653)
        - Chapter XXII (Box 19, Folder 654)
        - Chapter XXIII (Box 19, Folder 655)
        - Chapter XXIV (Box 19, Folder 656)
        - Chapter XXV (Box 19, Folder 657)
        - Chapter XXVI (Box 19, Folder 658)
        - Chapter XXVII (Box 19, Folder 659)
        - Chapter XXVIII (Box 19, Folder 660)
        - Chapter XXIX (Box 19, Folder 661)
        - Chapter XXX (Box 19, Folder 662)
        - Chapter XXXI (Box 19, Folder 663)
        - Chapter XXXII (Box 20, Folder 664)
        - Chapter XXXIII (Box 20, Folder 665)
        - Chapter XXXIV (Box 20, Folder 666)
        - Chapter XXXV (Box 20, Folder 667)
        - Chapter XXXVI (Box 20, Folder 668)
        - Chapter XXXVII (Box 20, Folder 669)
        - Chapter XXXVIII (Box 20, Folder 670)
        - Chapter XXXIX (Box 20, Folder 671)
        - Chapter XL (Box 20, Folder 672)
      - First draft of Part V, AMs
        - pp. 1-100 (Box 20, Folder 673)
        - pp. 101-200 (Box 20, Folder 674)
        - pp. 201-300 (Box 20, Folder 675)
        - pp. 301-400 (Box 20, Folder 676)
        - pp. 401-500 (Box 20, Folder 677)
        - pp. 501-600 (Box 21, Folder 678)
        - pp. 601-700 (Box 21, Folder 679)
        - pp. 701-781 (Box 21, Folder 680)
      - Draft of Part V, AMs
        - Chapter XLI (Box 21, Folder 681)
        - Chapter XLII (Box 21, Folder 682)
        - Chapter XLIII (Box 21, Folder 683)
        - Chapter XLIV (Box 21, Folder 684)
        - Chapter XLV (Box 21, Folder 685)
        - Chapter XLVI (Box 21, Folder 686)
        - Chapter XLVII (Box 21, Folder 687)
        - Chapter XLVIII (Box 21, Folder 688)
        - Chapter XLIX (Box 21, Folder 689)
        - Chapter L (Box 21, Folder 690)
        - Chapter LI (Box 21, Folder 691)
        - Chapter LII (Box 21, Folder 692)
        - Chapter LIII (Box 21, Folder 693)